aditor.com 2015-10-31

# Privacy-Policy | Aditor

_August 24, 2015_

**Introduction**

Aditor is a global provider of digital media and data management technology for advertisers and agencies. Aditor’s platform (the “Platform”) activates data, automates execution, and optimizes advertising interactions across addressable media—delivering greater performance, transparency, and control to marketers and a better experience to consumers.

This Privacy Statement presents Aditor’s privacy policy, including privacy practices for data choice, use and collection via our Platform and on the [www.Aditor.com](http://www.mediamath.com/) website (the “Website”).

**The Aditor Platform**

Aditor is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of Internet users. Accordingly, we adhere to applicable industry guidelines, and will continue to review and update our privacy policy and procedures to ensure the safety and protection of consumer information.

Aditor complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Aditor has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification page, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

Aditor is an active member of the industry associations that govern the policies around online consumer privacy, including: the Interactive Advertising Bureau (‘IAB’) in the US, Brazil, Canada, and the UK; the Digital Advertising Alliance (‘DAA’) in the US, EU, and Canada; and the Network Advertising Initiative (‘NAI’) ([www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)). Aditor complies with the cross-industry DAA Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising in the US, EU, and Canada, and the 2013 NAI Code of Conduct, and we believe that these programs’ principles help protect and ensure individual consumer privacy.

Aditor uses a DAA-Approved platform to comply with the ‘Enhanced Notice’ standard as dictated by the aforementioned self-regulatory principles. As part of this service, advertisements served by the Platform are delivered with icons that serve as a signal to consumers when behavioral data has been used. Through the icon, consumers can learn how their information is being used and by what companies, and access tools to control the collection and use of their information.

**Platform Data Collection and Use**

At Aditor, we think it’s important to provide transparency so that you have a better idea of which data might be collected by us and can make informed decisions.

In the course of delivering an ad to you via the Platform, Aditor does not collect data such as your name, address, phone number, or social security number. Aditor does collect data that is considered non-personally identifiable and pseudonymous data in most jurisdictions in which we operate. Aditor recognizes that, in certain contexts, Internet Protocol (IP) addresses and other pseudonymous information may be considered personal data in some jurisdictions. Aditor collects non-personally identifiable and pseudonymous data about your device via the Platform, to target ads and measure the effectiveness of ads on behalf of Aditor’s advertisers. This non-personally identifiable and pseudonymous information includes data like:

Domain Type | .com, .net, .edu, etc.  
---|---  
Standard Data | Common information found in every communication sent over the internet. Using this information, Aditor can infer information such as: browser type (e.g., Chrome or Internet Explorer); operating system (e.g., Mac OS or Windows); browser language (e.g., English or Spanish); Internet Protocol (IP) address; and Internet service provider (e.g., Comcast or Verizon).  
Clickstream Data | Aditor can collect data regarding your use of our clients’ sites and pages on the Internet.  
  
Aditor may use this non-personally identifiable and pseudonymous data to create data segments, and these data segments are generally based upon the websites that you visit. Aditor also receives information from third-party data providers that create non-personally identifiable behavioral, contextual, and demographic segments for our clients to use in targeting ads through the Platform.

Aditor does not collect data or create data segments that are based upon what we consider to be sensitive information (for example, we don’t use any data segments to determine credit worthiness, for insurance underwriting or similar purposes). Clients may use health-related segments (which are not comprised of sensitive health data) such as an inferred interest in health and wellness or cough medicine and allergy medications.

**Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Ad Targeting Technologies**

Like most digital marketing platforms, Aditor uses “cookies” and other technologies to enhance users’ experiences on the web, to deliver more relevant ads, and for ad delivery and reporting via the Platform.

Aditor cannot use these technologies to personally identify you, and these technologies should not damage your system or files. Aditor uses these technologies to help recognize a unique computer or device so that the Platform is able to deliver relevant advertising and measure the impact of that advertising. Your browser, computer, or mobile device is assigned a unique Aditor ID the first time Aditor serves an ad to it or identifies it on a client’s website. This unique ID may be stored in a file on your computer or mobile device. Along with the other information we collect via the Platform as described above, this unique ID helps us deliver more relevant ads to you. The ID and other information collected via the Platform can also help our advertising clients measure your activity on their sites and determine the effectiveness of advertisements delivered via the Platform. This information can then be used by our advertising clients to better cater to your needs and deliver to you ads for the types of products in which you might be interested. None of these technologies enable us to personally identify an individual. Instead, they enable the Platform to determine within a reasonable level of confidence that the computer or device we served an ad to on Monday may be the same computer or device on which we observed a purchase on Tuesday.

The types of technologies used via the Platform include:

  * **Cookies**  – Cookies are small text files that contain a string of characters. Aditor uses cookies to uniquely identify an Internet browser. Certain browsers or browser settings sometimes block cookies, and cookies may not work effectively on some mobile devices.
  * **Pixel Tags**  – Pixel tags (also commonly known as web beacons) are used to help web publishers understand how visitors interact with their websites. Pixel tags are transparent images, iFrames, or JavaScript that are placed on a site. The use of a pixel tag allows a website to measure the actions of the visitor opening the page that contains the tag.
  * **Statistical IDs**  – Statistical IDs are created via an algorithm using non-personally identifiable and pseudonymous information about your computer or device, including your operating system, user-agent string, IP address (in jurisdictions where this is not considered to be personal data), Internet browser, installed fonts, and similar information. This information makes your computer or device distinct enough for our systems to determine within a reasonable probability that they are encountering the same computer or device.

None of these technologies, whether individually or as a whole, are used via the Platform to identify individual people. Rather, they are used to uniquely identify a computer or device within a certain level of confidence that enables the Platform to function and serve more relevant ads.

**Mobile**

### Mobile Advertising IDs

  * Apple’s iOS IDFA can be reset by the user at any time. Users can opt out of all remarketing by enabling a device setting called “Limit Ad Tracking” (LAT), which restricts advertisers from using the IDFA for behavioral advertising. You can learn how to limit ad tracking on your iOS device or to reset your IDFA here: [IDFA Opt-Out](http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4228).
  * Similar to IDFA for Apple devices, Android devices pass Google Advertising ID, which provides the same type of device-specific, unique, resettable ID for advertising as Apple IDFA or IFA. You can learn more about how identifiers on mobile are used for advertising and receive instruction for how to opt out of mobile advertising on the [Google Privacy & Terms](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/)webpage.

**Data Retention – How Long is Data Stored on the Platform?**

Cookies set via the Platform expire after 13 months or less. After 13 months, we expire the unique ID and targeting segments that are associated with your browser, computer, or device. Aditor retains log-level data in the Platform for up to 13 months and maintains aggregate data (which cannot be associated to any individual device) for up to three years.

**To Opt Out of Interest-Based Advertising – Aditor’s Consumer Choice Mechanism**

Advertising supports the free Internet. It is the primary way that most website and app publishers make money in order to produce the content consumers want. Not all advertising shown to consumers is relevant to their interests, though. Interest-based advertising is advertising that tries to make the ads you see more interesting and relevant to you based on the types of sites you visit online and other non-personally identifiable information.

Without interested-based advertising, you will still see ads, but those ads are not likely to have anything to do with products or services you care about. With interest-based advertising, you receive ads and offers that are more likely to be useful to you.

There is also a second benefit to you: companies that create websites and apps rely on the revenue from interest-based advertising to support the rich array of content they produce. Without that revenue, the content would either be unavailable or consumers would have to pay for it directly.

Interest-based advertising does  **not**  depend on information that is personally identifiable to you, such as your name, address, phone number, etc.

If you do not want the benefits of interest-based advertising, there is a simple procedure that allows you to deactivate this feature. In order to “opt out” of the benefits of interest-based advertising from the Aditor Platform, you may click here:

**_Please note that you will still see ads if you opt out._**  The ads will just not be as relevant to you.

When you opt out, we record the opt-out on our servers and will attempt to place an HTTP opt-out cookie onto your computer or device and attempt to make similar opt-out notations in the local storage and cache of your browser. We use local storage and the browser cache to make our opt-out more persistent to honor your choice. In most instances, even if you delete your cookies, we are able to maintain your opt-out notation in local storage or the browser cache.

**_Please note that if you clear your cookies or the cache of your browser or device, or if you use a different browser or device, you may need to renew your opt-out choice._**

When you opt out, Aditor also dissociates the unique ID associated with your browser or device from the associated segment data. Further, Aditor stops tracking and stops serving interest-based advertising on the browsers or devices associated with that ID.

You may learn more about online behavioral advertising and opt out of other online advertising companies that are also members of applicable self-regulatory organizations by visiting their opt-out links:

  * Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) – <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>
  * Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) – <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>
  * Digital Advertising Alliance Canada (DAAC) – <http://youradchoices.ca/choices>
  * Digital Advertising Alliance EU (EDAA) – <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>

If you have questions, please contact us at [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

**Disclosure**  
Aditor may publish or otherwise make public anonymous, aggregate, or summary information regarding site visitors and campaigns run on behalf of our clients. Aditor may share visitor-level data with a client, restricted to include only data associated with the client’s campaigns. Aditor will never share visitor-level data with any third parties other than as outlined within this policy. There also may be instances when we may disclose visitor information in order to: protect the legal rights of Aditor or its employees, agents and contractors; protect the safety and security of visitors to our site; protect against fraud; or to comply with the law or legal process. If Aditor sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of assets or is otherwise involved in a merger or business transfer, we may transfer visitor information to a third party as part of that transaction.

**The Aditor Website, www.Aditor.com**

**Data Collection and Retention on our Website**

Aditor only collects personal information on our corporate Website when visitors choose to reveal it to us. For example, when you contact us to request a demonstration of our products or services or to otherwise send us questions, we will collect personal information such as name and email address. Aditor uses non-personally identifiable and pseudonymous information from the Website log files to determine how you found out about us, what your interests are regarding our services, and how to further improve our site and our service towards you. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Cookies set via the Website expire after at most two years.

**Communications From the Site**  
When you sign up for our services on the Website, we will use your name and email address to send newsletters to you. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or by contacting us via email at [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

**Service Providers**  
When you sign up for our services on the Website, we may provide your information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities, such as an email service provider to send emails on our behalf or a recruitment partner to process job application data. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

**Technologies Used on the Website**  
Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts are used by Aditor and our partners (such as service providers), affiliates, or analytics or service providers (e.g., video providers and email service providers to send email on our behalf). These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Website, tracking users’ movements around the Website and to gather demographic information about our Website visitors as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. Additionally, some of our third party service providers, with whom we partner use Flash cookies to collect and store information to better provide you with video content.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include IP address, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

**Social Media Features and Widgets**  
The Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets such as the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on the Website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Testimonials**  
We display testimonials from satisfied clients on the Website in addition to other endorsements. We obtain client permission to place these testimonials on the Website. If you are a client who wishes to update or delete your testimonial, please contact us at [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

**Public Forums**  
The Website offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Additional Information Applicable to our Website and Platform**

**Information Pertaining to Children**

Aditor’s products and services are designed for those 13 years of age and older. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. If the company is made aware that it has received personally identifiable information from someone under 13, we will use reasonable efforts to remove that information from our records.

**Consumer Choice and Access**  
Aditor will allow an individual access to their personal information to the extent it is available and allow the individual to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate information, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the privacy of the individual in the case in question, or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated. If you’d like us to update, correct, delete, or deactivate any other personal information that you have provided to us, please send your request to us at [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com) and we will respond to your request within 30 days.

**Security and Data Integrity**  
Aditor uses commercially reasonable measures to safeguard data in our possession against loss, theft, and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification. No transmission of data over the Internet, however, is guaranteed to be completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of Aditor to intercept or access transmissions or communications unlawfully. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. Aditor processes information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected. To the extent necessary for those purposes, we take reasonable steps to ensure that any information in our care is accurate, complete, current, and reliable for its intended use. If you have any questions about security on the Website or through the Platform, you can contact us at [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com).

**Policy Revisions**  
From time to time Aditor may revise this privacy policy. If we make revisions that change or affect whether or how we collect or use personally identifiable information we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. Therefore, you should review it periodically so that you are up-to-date on our most current policies and practices.

**Links**  
This privacy statement applies solely to the Platform and Website of Aditor. Aditor’s Website contains links to other sites, and the ads delivered by the Platform may run on a variety of other sites. Please be aware that Aditor is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

**Enforcement, Questions and Complaints**  
_Enforcement:_  
Aditor has implemented processes to ensure compliance with this privacy policy and periodically verifies that the policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and accessible, and in conformity with the NAI Code of Conduct. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns by emailing [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com) and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of information.  
To address any issues regarding our compliance with the NAI Code of Conduct, Aditor, along with the NAI and other NAI members have created a compliance program that incorporates attestation reviews, a consumer complaint process, sanctions, and annual reporting to help ensure that member companies keep their promises to you and abide by the NAI Code of Conduct. Please refer to the [NAI site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) for more information.

_Privacy Complaints by European Union Citizens:_  
In compliance with the US–EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Aditor commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union and Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Aditor at [privacy@Aditor.com](mailto:privacy@mediamath.com)

To opt-out:

<http://youradchoices.ca/choices>

<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>

Or email us [optout@aditor.com](mailto:optout@aditor.com)
